

### Profile

Regional Sales Manager with more than 7+ years experience in sales and management, supervising business development staff, planning and executing sales strategies nationally. Previous year, achieved 120% of yearly sales goal by bringing in \$100,000 in new business and managing assigned territories from \$3.6 million to \$4.5 million. Seeking a position in regional sales management

### Employment History

Regional Sales Manager at Senju Fire Protection Corp , Irvine, CA  $_{\rm May\,2022-Present}$ 

- Manages fire protection and plumbing distributor partnerships and key customers across six regional markets.
- Implement sales initiatives to generate new business in the building materials and fire sprinkler industries on new residential and commercial construction projects.
- Develops relationships and holds meetings with executive leadership to promote fire sprinkler products in accordance with the NFPA 13, 13R, and 13 systems building codes.

# Corporate Planning Manager at Senju Fire Protection Corp., Irvine, CA

September 2020 — April 2022

- Achieved corporate goals by implementing corporate strategies to market new products, target key prospects, and acquire new customers.
- Trained and developed business development and inside sales staff to support the growth of the company objectives, sales and profit goals.
- Implemented specific territory initiatives for sales teams, developed new business models and partnered with management to sustain growth.

# Corporate Planning Assistant Manager at Senju Fire Protection Corp, Irvine, CA

January 2019 — September 2020

- Scheduled 2-3 business trips per month to maintain relationships with major prospects and existing accounts in assigned territory.
- Responsible for managing the new Corporate Planning department as well as trained business development representatives on effective sales processes and providing them with sales advice.

## Inside Sales Representative at Senju Fire Protection Corp. , Irvine, CA

March 2018 — January 2019

#### **Details**

Irvine, CA USA (619) 709-7373 asuzukicruz@gmail.com

#### Sales Skills

**Territory Management** 

Negotiation

**Account Management** 

**Business Development** 

#### **Soft Skills**

Collaboration

Leadership

**Growth Mindset** 

Communication

#### **Tools**

Salesforce CRM, Microsoft Excel, Outlook, Teams, and Word

#### Links

LinkedIn

- Ensured existing customer purchases were maintained and expanded by promoting new fire sprinkler products.
- Improved order processing accuracy from 85% to 99% using simple and effective operational tools.

# Assistant Sales Manager at Morinaga Nutritional Foods, Inc, Torrance, CA

March 2013 — October 2016

- Developed and managed relationships with Natural Foods Chain accounts like Whole Foods, Sprouts, and UNFI through a national network of food brokers.
- Conducted new product launch presentations to key accounts and distributors and traveled often to enhance product visibility at store level.

### Education

International Business, San Diego State University, San Diego, CA  ${\it May}\,2006-{\it May}\,2011$ 

• Emphasis in Marketing and Japanese Language.

### International Business, Gunma University, Gunma, Japan

May 2009 — May 2010

• Foreign Exchange Student Program.